SARAH K. RUSSELL

11677 Leavenworth Dr, Conifer, CO 80433 | 615-424-9519 | sarah@skrdesign.com | skrdesign.com

SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER

Over a decade of experience working professionally as a Senior Web Developer. Known for improving practices and production time, writing well-structured code that is reusable, thoroughly tested, and up to current best practices and ADA compliant. An excellent eye for design and attention to detail that is useful in all my work comes from my graphic design background.

STRONG WORKING KNOWLEDGE OF

- HTML5
- CSS3, CSS Pre-processing SASS, SCSS, LESS
- JavaScript, jQuery, ES6
- Accessibility Design and Development
- Web Content Accessibility (WCAG) AA ADA, Section 508 standards

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ProfitStars; a Jack Henry & Associates Company | Brentwood, TN | January 2014 – April 2019 Advanced Web Developer

Fintech company. Built over 90 responsive websites for financial institutions that precisely matched the designers' mockups and wireframes. Remote work requiring excellent organization, verbal, and written communication skills.

- Contributed to the transition of our build process and current client sites to include Web Content Accessibility (WCAG) 2.0 AA ADA. Wrote documentation for the Web Solutions Department and implemented the changes on client sites.
- Review UI/UX designs for any technical issues. Websites built with HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Gulp, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, on Bootstrap framework. Version control with GIT, SEO optimized, cross-browser compatibility, and device tested.

SKR Design LLC | Conifer, CO | May 2003 - Present

Freelance Senior Web Developer and Designer

Occasional freelance web projects. Design and develop user-friendly, engaging websites with intuitive navigation that meet the clients' needs, specifications, and goals.

- Handle all aspects of the website project: branding, design, development, hosting, adding the site to the content management system (CMS), launching, and perform routine maintenance.
- Provided independent music bands with websites, email newsletters, social media marketing, merchandising, and retail support.

Acxiom | Nashville, TN | July 2009 - January 2014

Content Developer

Technology and data marketing company. Coded high-quality business to customer email campaigns by transforming client provided mockups into responsive emails. Promoted from Content Specialist.

- Improved coding practices, cut production time, and implemented responsive coding guidelines across the department.
- Content lead for Sam's Club, American Cancer Society, Procter & Gamble, and Qwest. Offered technical suggestions and recommendations directly to the client.
- Member of the Platform Quality Assurance Group that reviewed current industry standards and implemented our findings across the company.

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Bootstrap framework, Foundation framework, developing without a framework
- Understanding of UX Design and UI Development
- Code versioning tools; Git, GitHub
- Content Management Systems (CMS), WordPress
- Search Engine Optimization (SEO)
- Google Analytics and Google Webmaster Tools
- Cross-browser compatibility and device testing
- Responsive Design
- Adobe Creative Suite, Sketch
- Webpack, NPM, Yarn, Gulp, Grunt, Babel, Node.js
- Beginner, currently learning; PHP

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Design, Visual Communications Design (Graphic Design)

University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, Canada

QUOTE

"Sarah takes on challenges and is determined to overcome obstacles. She is not satisfied until she is 100% done with a project. She is fantastic at communicating the best way for the best situation. Sarah is great at taking on the initiative of learning new things."

- Annual Review quote by K. Wynns, Supervising Manager at ProfitStars.

PORTFOLIO

www.skrdesign.com